Which plan is better HDFC Eggo Optima
Secure and Aditya Birlas Active and
Max One is backed by one of the largest
banks in the world and the other is backed by one
of the most significant and trusted
names in India Aditya Birla Group One
offers a to X cover and the other offers you
zero premium if you follow their help.
HDFC Virgo comes with a 2X cover from
day one of policy insurance at no
extra cost.  Aditya Birla does not give
you the 2X cover but can make your premium
zero at the time of renewal if you achieve the
help goals they set after running their app.  But these are
promises and we believe you and your
customers do not only want promises.  We
want to know what the insurer will actually
pay claims when the time comes.  So in this
video we won't just talk about the shiny
product features at someone or the other will always say
you will go several layers deeper.
I will use my 20 years of experience
and of course deep data back research to break
down both these plans clearly.  Mahavir
Chopra, the Founder and Chief Executive
Officer of Beshak.org.  India's only
insurance platform that is 100%
neutral 100% not influenced by
insurance commissions.  Now here is what we will be
covering in this video.  Number one you
will do a quick overview of both the companies.
Number to a comparison of their unique features
back by hard data behind these two
plants.  Number three, a side-by-side
comparison of the core benefits that matter in
real life.  Number four, a detailed look at the
claims experience and the customer service
experience, including real-world claims
performance data.  Number five, a clear
comparison of the prying.  How much money will
an insurance company charge to provide a plan?
And finally, The Beshaq Ratings, India's
only independent insurance ratings
where we convert all this research into one
single data back score.  So that you do not have to worry how to know how
the products are
getting compared for each of the parameters
that we are going to discuss today.  Now a
quick overview of Aditya Birla Health
Insurance Company.  Founded in 2015, it is
a joint venture between MMI Holdings
and Aditya Birla Group.  Aditya Birla
Health is a stand alone health insurance
company focused only on health insurance as
a business with around Rs 4300 crore of
premium. It stands at one of the India's
leading stand alone health insurance
companies.  Now a quick overview of HDFC
Ergo as a company.  Founded in 2002, HDFC
Ergo is a joint venture between HDFC Ergo
International.  They are being in the space for 20
plus years the reputation that comes from
HDFC is a brand their network bank
network has helped them cross a turnover of
around 8500 crores in 2025 ok so let's do
a quick overview and understanding of the
USPs and how both of them compare with each other
the USP of HDFCO is the most talked
about feature about HDFCO it is a 2X
benefit where you get a 2X cover
from day one without paying anything
extra.  Actually you pay extra but that is how they
sell this feature.  Now the second
feature is a comparative feature.  I'll take it
Ceperelli.  I will go to Aditya Birla
first.  Aditya Birlas main USP what it is being talked about
and Aditya
Birla Health when it started it also spoke about this very very
regularly in
their campuses is basically bringing health
and health insurance together.  So what it does
is basically in this plan.  It not only
covers you basically for hospitalization and
cure which is usually the job of a health
insurance policy.  It also wants you to
keep healthy and how does it do it?  It
basically offers you a gamified kind of a,
where you basically follow their goals that they offer
you.  And you get points.  Now you can
use these points basically to pay premiums
and get claim reductions. You can use
this money to basically pay for these
reductions. You can also buy equipment
on their app or on their website.  So these are the
things that you can do and the activities that
you can do are also very
simple.  You give are mostly
activities related to a basically walking
goals.  Or any other kind of activity that they
offer on the app.  Or it could be basically
completing a health assessment or doing a
medical check.  All this gives you points,
which you can then use to basically pay
premiums or do anything else on their app.
It is basically the campaign or the offer and the pitch
of this plan is that your premium can become
zero at the time of renewal.  If
you follow these steps or
whatever goals they offer you, you do that.  So it
basically says that you become healthy and we
will reduce your sum in your premium.  Not
your sum insure your premium to zero.  Now
moving on to the next feature which is
again a feature that we found to be very
interesting for Aditya Birla Activ Max.
It is basically a feature where as an add on you can
basically when you buy a multi tenure
policy you buy a normally we buy a five year
policy but let's see you buy a two year three
and five year policy the sum insured that you
basically buy for the next few years can be
pre used by you in the first year or
the second year.  So let's say let me give you an
example if you are confused.
I take a 5 year policy from Lets with
sum insured of Rs 10 lakh.  So the total covered for one
year is 10 laces, I can usually use only
10 laces.  But this plan basically says that let say in
the number year number two if you have a
claim of 20 less.  Now your next cover
was Year Three Year Four for which you have already paid the premium.
You can use that cover
in years too if you have a big claim.
So all these things basically help you solve
the problem of big claims.  Now coming to
big claims is the next add on of this
product which is called basically the
unlimited care add on.  The Unlimited Care add-
on is becoming very, very
prevalent now in the new plans that are
coming in the country.  Ah the basic feature of
this plan is that you can basically make for unlimited sum insured in one claim in your life
or your family's life ah life
time.
So typically late,
you get what a cover of late, 20 lax, 25
lax, now we don't know how basically healthcare
costs are going to go up, we don't know what
kinds of diseases can happen.  So We Don't Know What Kind
of Covers We Need.  So this
kind of a plan basically tells you that
once in your life you can take
as much money as you need from the insurance company to solve your disease.
Which is a
great feature.  It actually solves the
uncertainty that typically exists about whether the
amount of cover I have is sufficient or not.  So
it is a great feature and it is an add on but it is a little complicated when I am
going to say this but please understand this better a little
carefully it is a fixed add on so what the
insurance company has done is that when you buy this
plan typically this add
on is you cannot remove this add on this is
back tendered into the price that the insurance
agent will offer you now even if I am
telling you it is a fixed add on looking at
this plan and if you are planning to
buy this plan you should check this add on also it is not there then
you should add it because this is a
beautiful feature any insurance company can
offer you so you should look at this feature.  Now why
I wanted to take this feature the last
even two it is a good feature is because HDFC
Ergo also offers something like the add on feature
that Aditya Birla offers.  Now it is called
a Limitless add on.  One person is saying
unlimited, one person is saying limitless, it has the same
meaning but the names are obviously different.
Now again in this case also you can
basically get an unlimited cover for one
claim in your lifetime if your sum insured
is less than 50 lakh.  And if your sum insured
is above Rs 50 lakh then you can take it twice.
Meaning the insurance company said if you
insure Rs 60 lakh or Rs 1 crore, whatever sum you take and then you would want to
use this feature you will be
able to use it twice in your lifetime
or your family's lifetime again like I said it is
a great feature it is an add on so whenever
you are basically looking at this
plan my recommendation would be that you should take this add on it is
a great ah a feature and
stands for uncertainty so we have
completed all the USPs of both these plans
now we move to the core benefits core
benefits are very good my work is made
very easy both the plans both the
plans basically offer no limits on
room rent.  So there is no room rent category limit
as such that you have to take a private room.  It's
not like you
basically have any kind of limit.  There
is a financial limit and the policy.  So it basically is a
no question ask.  You
can take the room you want.  You don't have to worry about
it. Pre & Post Hospitalization One
Offers HDFC Virgo Offers 6080 Aditya Birla
Offers 90 180.  Ok.  It is very good.
Both are good.  Third is day care
treatments.  Both offer all treatments
covered.  No Limit is great.  You have
any type of dare treatment that is
under 24 hours, both are ready to cover.
Domiciliary Treatment Again All
Treatments Covered No Limit.  These are all
comprehensive pluses
from the insurance companies we review, which generally do
not have any limits.  So it would be
great.  There are no issues with the core features.
You should understand the USB,
understand the price, understand the rest of the claim performance and
then buy the policy after talking to the advisor.
But it
is very important to understand.  That's why I am telling you.   There are
no limits even in dominary treatment.
All analysis are covered.  There is
no limit.  Modern treatment basically has
no limits.  There are many plans
which have limits.  50% of the sum
insured is covered up to Rs 1 lakh.  This all happens.
Both these plans are saying
that brother, you can take whatever you want, your
sum insured will obviously be limited
but you can take modern
treatments if you want.  Now organ donors are
also covered up to some insured.  So
basically if you see, there is
no limit in anyone.  There is only a 90 days 180
days limit for pre and post hospitalization in Aditya Birla.
60 and 180 days is
pre and post hospitalization for HDF
se which is good enough.  So we completed the
comparison of all the core benefits.  Now we move
to the good to have a comparison of benefits.
Now Consumables Cover Both offers you
consumables cover up to the sum insured and in
both the cases it is an inbuilt feature.  You do
n't have to pay anything extra.   The
insurance company is saying that brother, all the
non-medical expenses that a hospital will
charge will also be covered.  I will pay, you don't have to pay anything
extra.  I'll basically I'll have
baked it into the base premium that you're
going to pay me.  Now the next feature is
basically the restoration feature.  In this
basically there is a difference.  In case of
HDFC Arbo the restoration happens only one
time which is inbuilt now in a year
restoration feature is what happens if your sum
insured ever gets exhausted in a year
basically it gets exhausted in between then you do not have a choice
to make a claim after that because
your cover gets exhausted you will have to
wait till next year but restoration basically
restores the sum insured for the remaining
period of time so if sum insured of 10 lakhs gets
exhausted in 6 months then the insurance
company is selling you ok you can use it again
10 lakhs can be used again and it is
for all kinds of illnesses unrelated related
illnesses you need
not worry HDFCO basically offers you a restoration
once in your policy time.  Aditya Birla
inbuilt offers you unlimited types.  In the
case of HDFC Ago, you can get unlimited if you want.
You have to pay extra.
Now the premium I've seen in the past for
taking for a few friends when I've
checked.  Unlimited Resolution has no
premium, no grade higher.  So
you can get unlimited in HDFCO also.
Now Moving On To Bonus.  In both the cases there is
an inbuilt bonus add on that is
available.  Now what does HDFCO offer?
In HDFCO your sum insured increases by 50% and
can go up to 100%.  So basically,
after the 2X cover that you were already getting, you are getting another
2X cover that the insurance
company is providing.  This bonus is guaranteed.
So it doesn't basically get linked with if
you make a claim and don't make a
claim.  It is largely about loyalty.  If you
continue with the same plan, you will
get a bonus.  In case of Aditya Birla
Activ Max also it is inbuilt.  But there is 100%
no claim bonus and you can get up to 5X.
If you have a cover of Rs 10 lakh, it can go up to Rs 50 lakh.
Again guaranteed you do not have any
kind of basically linkage to
claims.  You just renew and you will
get it.  Now moving on to one feature
which is there in Aditya Birla but not
there in HDFC Arboz Optima Secure.  It is called
a durable medical equipment
cover.  This is a cover where normally the
health insurance company covers medical
equipment, external
equipment like wheelchair,
prosthetic device, ventilator, there is a
lot of list mentioned here, there is
oxygen concentrator, we see that
senior citizens need many things out of
this, you can get all those things
covered under Aditya Birla Active One
by paying extra premiums, this is
not available in HDFC Urbus Optima
Secure, if you are
taking a policy for someone who is 50-55 years old
and someone who is a senior citizen, then
taking this add-on makes sense because it actually gives you certain things that may be
useful, very very means can be useful if
unfortunately such a situation arises.
Quickly moving on to the waiting periods.
Now waiting periods are standard
in both.  Quickly, the waiting period of 30 months and 30 days is
in the first year.
All policies have a provision for sickness.
You cannot claim in the first 30 days.
You can claim for accident within
30 days.  Then you can claim for all the
illness related claims.  There is a two year
waiting period for specified illnesses.
That is there in both the policies.  Listed
illnesses are diseases and treatments
that you cannot get covered for in
the first two years after which you can make claims.
For existing diseases, both have a
three-year waiting period, 36 months waiting
period. In both, this PED waiting
period is called PED very normally
in the industry. Now a days,
customers have also started calling it PED. You
can modify it in case of HDFCO for four listed
conditions A, B, C, D. These are called
asthma, blood pressure, cholesterol and
diabetes. You can get cover after 30 days,
so there is no need to wait for three years.  You
can get a cover from 30 days for these three-four
illnesses that I just mentioned about.
Obviously, it is something that is up to the insurance
company.  If your diabetes
is very high then the insurance company may not give you insurance
but you can pay a premium and you can get
this modification done.  This is typically useful
for anyone who has an existing
disease out of these four.  And I don't want to wait
for three years for the claim to be valid.
What if the claim comes before me?
Similarly there is in the case of Aditya Birla.
They don't cover four.  They cover seven chronic
conditions under their Chronic Care add-on.
Now there is no waiting period of even 30 days.
They are saying that you have zero
waiting period
in this policy and you can claim it immediately.
I quickly read the illnesses in it.  Diabetes,
hypertension, eczema, hyperlipidemia
which is basically the ABCD.  These
four which I told you earlier are the same.
COPD is one of them.  That is also something that
you can get.  Obesity is becoming very
common in India.  So it's
again interesting that they are covering.
And if you have had angioplasty before one year then in that
specific case also you can get
a day one coverage for these diseases if
you pay extra so this is very easy this is a
good thing for people who are going to let's say buy this
policy and they have a
disease out of these chronic illnesses and
conditions if one of these exist.  Moving on
to customer service.  No such
parameter of customer service is available in the world.
Not available in India.  IDI
does not publish it nor does your insurance
company.  We do our own audits on the
insurance company website and on the Twitter of
the insurance company.  Meaning, the insurance company which handles this also
checks the toll free number to see whether
people actually pick up the phone or not.
Because the biggest service an
insurance company can provide is to pick up the phone and
answer it.  So we test that.
Now in case of basically customer service there are
two parameters which I will quickly
tell you.  The first parameter is
comparison of toll free.
Basically both the companies are average in comparison to toll free.  Both are
equally bad and equally good.  Well then.
This means that you do
not have any different features in comparison.  So leave it.  In
case of Twitter basically Aditya Birla fares better it has been
marked as quick compare
to average HDFCO then on Twitter you will
get better service than Aitya Birla compared to
HDFC Ago.  Now the most important thing that we will discuss,
which is important for us, for you and for
everyone, is claims.  Variantly, no matter
how many good features you get, we can
talk about everything, meaning you can get modification of waiting periods
but if you are not going to get
your aim then what is the whole point right so that is what we are
going to compare now
three four quick important parameters will compare
between HDFC Argo and Aditya
Birla One Active One Max the first one is
speed of claim settlement means how many
claims an insurance company settles in the
first 30 days of receiving those claims in
case of HDFC Argo Optima Secure it is
96.63% in case of Aditya Birla Active One
it is 99.90% meaning they are settling
almost all the claims they receive within the
first 30 days that they receive the claim.  The
next is claim complaints.  In this case,
basically it is how many complaints are coming to the
insurance company?  How many
complaints is the insurance company getting compared
to the claims that they have received.
In this case both are equally good and bad.  This
number is reasonable in my view.  0.15% in
case of SFC and 0.16% in case of Aditya
Ilies.  So it's a decent number.  Now
going to Incurred Claim Ratio.  This is a
ratio which tells you how much an
insurance company is using the money that it
receives as part of its premium into
claims.  So, if the premium is ₹100, then
how much amount is going towards the claim.
These are many ratios for you to
understand that the insurance company should be
profitable and should
also pay the claims on time.  This is its ratio.
So in this case, the typical rule of
thumb in the industry is that it should be
between 60 to 80%.  Now
in the case of HDFC Ergo the number is 87.04% so
their incurred claim ratio is a bit high
compared to the normal thumb rule that we look at should be
80 so it is 87.04 so this means
that the insurance company is paying a lot of claims
compared to the premium that it
is collecting but also means that
premiums can increase further.  Compare this to
AID Birla's claim incurred ratio
or called incurred claim ratio.  Its
ICR is 75.97% which falls within the
rule of form.  So it's doing well in this
ratio.  Now moving on to claim rejection
ratio.  This is a very important ratio.
If I pick up any five industry experts and
ask them
what is the most important ratio?  If you have to check the claims then
this is the rejection ratio.  So it
is very important to compare this.  It is
different that you compare claim rejection
ratio.  This is a ratio which adds up
claim reputation and claim rejection into
one and then calculates the ratio.
If you want to see more about it, then
of course.  But you can understand the difference.  Ah HDFC
Ergo Optima Secure or HDFC Argos
claim rejection ratio is 2.53% Aditya
Birla's Active & Max Aditya Birla as an
insurance company not Aditya Birla
Active & Max has a claim rejection
ratio of 4.06% so if you compare then
HDFCO rejects less claims.
Aditya Birla rejects most of the claims.
But if I compare all the insurance companies then
Aditya
Birla is doing reasonably well, it is not a
bad ratio.  4% is a decent ratio.
Obviously HDFC Ergo is doing much better
compared to Aditya Birla.  So those are the
ratios that you need to understand.  Now
we have compared all the important things.
Compare the products.  We understood all the
USPs.  We Understood did a roll call of
all the important core features.  We have
understood the service.  We have understood the
claims.  Now let us understand
how much money the insurance company will charge for all this?
Which is very different to understand.  Now
for Mr. Kumar, which is our standard use
case, we always carry the same sample.
30 year old two adults meaning his wife
and one kid who is one year old living in
Mumbai what is the premium difference for 10 less sum insured
?  The premium for HDFC
Argo Optima Secure is Rs 2435 in case of
Aditya Birla is Rs 18584 while we
recorded this video.  So the Premium Has
a Difference.  There is a difference of ₹6,000 between 18,000 and 24,000.
Which is almost like 30%
difference.  But there is a caveat which you have to
understand that for Rs 24,000 HDFCO is
giving you 2X cover on Day Zero.   The
Active One product has other
features which you will have to understand to understand its price.
But here Aditya HDFCO has backed in the 2X cover.
Sorry not Aditya
Billa has not done it.  So,
HDFCO is also charging you the same premium for 2X cover.
Ok?  That is something that you should understand.
24,000, 18,000 approx
is the comparison.  Now the most important thing to
understand.  How do we compare all these things that we discussed
?  Meaning, somewhere
insurance company A is good, somewhere
insurance company B is good,
who is basically good in claims, somewhere
someone is good in product, should I
see this, should I see that, how should I see it?  For this
we have created Something Which Is Called a
Course Ratings.  Which basically does a
relative comparison across all the companies to
understand that if
we put all the companies in an exam for this product and
ask them which one is the best in the product
?  Who is good at claims,
who is good at service?  So how many
marks will each of the three get and then
who is on top in total marks?  That is what we
understand through ratings, of course, is what we have
tried to solve.  We are the only
company in India which does this.  And we are
the only company in India that does this neutrally independently without
taking
any commissions from insurance companies and any
kind of marketing fee/advertising fee.
So quickly, HDFC
Eggo Opt Secure gets five out of
five in product benefits.  The best product in the market
today in our view is HDFCOS Optima
Secure.  And Aditya Birla does not fall
very short.  Slightly less.  4.85 out of
five.  So it's reasonably good.  Both Are
Quiet in the Same Zone is what I would say.
The next is customer service.
HDFCO again hits a five in customer service.  So, according to
our audits, HDFCO is
getting five out of five in terms of service parameters.  Compare
that to Aditya Birla also gets 4.72.  So
this is also quite in the zone.  And it overall when
I compare this and I remember the other
reviews that have been done.  It is doing quite
well compared to many other companies.
Specific comparison to stand-alone dedicated
health insurance companies.
Now Comparing Claims
Experience.  Here the game turned upside down.
Here HDFC R Go gets 4.85 out of
five.  Aditya Birla is getting five out of
five.  So they are checking all the boxes of all
the parameters that are available to us
publicly for us to understand how the
insurance companies are performing on
claims.  So A Aditya Birla is
hitting a sixer in claims.  HDFC Ergo is
hitting a sixer in product benefits.  And
overall, if you look at it,
what difference is there in the ratings?  The overall rating is
4.94. In the case of HDFC Arbo
Optima Secure and Aditya Birla Active
One, it is 4.90. This is basically like a
clash of two titans, right?  Both are big
companies.  This happens like it used to happen
in school, in college.   There are
two people who are fighting.  Who
will come first?  It is like that.  Both are equal.
Just buy .04 HDFC Virgo is better.  Right?
Now after this you would be thinking that okay I
understand all this.  What is the meaning
?  How to understand?  How to get the product.  So what this
gives you is a standard
understanding.  It gives you
a standard understanding of how these
products are fairing for a standard
individual in the market and a standard
family in the market.  If You Want
Customized Advice.  If you basically want to
understand whether this product is right for your personal needs or
not.  In that
specific case it is different to first
note down all your needs and then map it
against the product what is available in the
market and then map it against all the other
things that are
available from that product and whether it
psychologically gives you comfort or not.  This
is one way.  The second way is to
transfer all these things to a specialist.
Find an expert.  Find as much time
as it takes you to find the right product.  Take
time out to find the right expert for you
and then consult them.
Give all your information you need to them.  And Then Let Them
Guide You How to Choose the Right Plan and
How to Buy the Right Plan.  And they can
actually help you also at the time of
claim.  Of course, we do this as well.
If you do not have such an expert
in your network.  You can come to this without any hesitation and
all these services that I just mentioned can be
offered for free.  Hope you like this
video.  If you have any questions about the
comparison of these two plans.  If You Have
Any Feedback To Give About How We Are
Conducting And Doing These Videos Reviews.
Do write us in the comments.  We will be more than
happy to answer.  We will be more than happy
to learn from you to understand if there is something that
we are missing.  And we would be more than
happy to basically
actually get you to give us feedback.  Because it
is the most important encouragement that we can get.
And since we are talking about encouragement, there is
one more thing I would like to tell you.
We take a lot of effort to do these
videos.  We have been here in this space.
Doing videos from almost four hours
now.  So it takes a lot of effort for
everybody here.  Not only me.  I'm only on
the camera.  There are so many people there right now for
people here to listen or
monitor what I am doing.  So from
that perspective, if you like our work, do
basically like the video, do subscribe to
the channel.  You will get other information, other
reviews, other comparisons that we will keep
doing and you get to learn about
insurance.  Thank you very much.